So again.
So here in this new section we will be talking about how to design an antenna.
Through this section we'll go through all the steps that we need to follow in order to design an antenna.
So first of all, we'll go through a small introduction that will present for us the phenomenon of resonance.
Then we'll be talking about the CART physical model.
And finally we'll present the antenna design.
So first of all, the introduction.
So first of all, here we need to understand the phenomenon of resonance.
So when we talk about resonance we talk about resonance of an electrical circuit.
Because an NFC card, which is composed by an antenna and the chip presents an electrical circuit.
Then we will try to understand the RF parameters needed for HF cards.
So for high frequency cards, which means for NFC cards, then we will learn about the purpose and methods
of antenna design.
After that, we will identify all the steps to be followed to design an antenna.
And finally we'll execute the right tests to validate the best solution.
So first of all, mechanical resonance is the tendency of a mechanical system to respond at greater
amplitude when the frequency of its oscillations matches the system's natural vibration frequency than
other frequencies.
This causes the system to oscillate with larger amplitude.
Then, when the force is applied at other frequencies.
For example, here a swing can be considered as a mechanical system where we have a phenomenon of resonance.
And the resonance frequency.
When you talk about resonance, we talk about resonance frequency which is presented by f0 equal one
divided by two multiplied by p multiplied by root square of l divided by g.
Then which is more important?
The resonance in electronic.
So in electrical circuit the resonance occurs because the collapsing magnetic field of the inductor
generates an electric current that charges the capacitor.
And then the discharging capacitor provides an electric current that builds the magnetic field in the
inductor.
So here we say the inductor.
We have the L which is a symbol of the inductor.
And when we have a current that passes through the inductor we have a magnetic field that generates.
So here for this system which is an RLC here we don't have the R, we don't have the the resistance.
But here it looks like an RLC circuit.
So the formula for the resonant frequency for this circuit is F0 equal one divided by two multiplied
by p multiplied by root square of l divided by c.
So what about the pick components?
So what about the contactless card components.
So a pick is composed by an inlay which is composed by an antenna.
And the chip.
So the antenna is the current loop or where we have the phenomenon of inductive inductive coupling is
generated and the chip is presented by a memory or a microprocessor.
Let's say also an integrated circuit.
So as you can see here in the picture.
So the antenna part we have the resistance and the inductance and the chip parts.
We have the capacitance.
So then we will talk about the cart physical model.
So as we said earlier, an NFC card or a contactless card or a pack is composed by an antenna and the
chip.
So the antenna is presented by an antenna inductance and an antenna resistance.
When the chip is presented by a chip input capacitance.
And here where the chip is activated.
So a pic when we put it into the field can be considered as an RLC circuit.
R for resistance, L for inductance and C for capacitance.
So when we have the phenomenon of resonance, the impedance of the inductance is equal to the impedance
of the capacitance, which give us that two multiplied by p multiplied by f0 multiplied by L is equal
to one divided by two multiplied by p multiplied by f0 multiplied by c, which means that f0 the resonance
frequency is equal to one divided by two multiplied by p multiplied by root square of l multiplied by
c.
And by the way, the current.
In the inductor, the inductance of the antenna element is equal to the maximum of the current of the
inductance of the antenna.
When we are in the resonance frequency.
So for example here we have a spice simulation.
So for example when we have the inductance of the of the of the antenna is equal to five micro Henry.
And when the capacitance is equal to 30 picofarad we have the resonance frequency equal to 1290 nine
megahertz.
And by the way when we talk about NFC system we talk about a frequency of 1350 six megahertz.
So this is the range the reference.
So regarding the RLC circuits, we have something that calls the bandwidth, which is the range frequency
where power dissipated is superior to half, which is presented by -three decibels of the full power.
So this is our bandwidth.
So we take we draw a line on -three decibels and then we extract F2 and f1.
So our bandwidth if is f2 minus by minus f1.
So then a very important parameter regarding the RLC circuits is the q factor, which is a factor that
determines the efficiency of an RC circuit.
And the formula for that is that q equal to f zero resonance frequency divided by the bandwidth, which
is also equal to the resistance multiplied by the root square of the capacitance divided by the inductance.
So now we will talk about the antenna design.
So for the antenna design we have four steps that we need to follow.
So first of all regarding the the integrated circuit parameters we need to get the data sheet the input
capacitance and the tuning frequency.
So when we get an integrated circuit which is included in the chip part, and when we get the data sheet,
and to check the data sheet of the integrated circuit, we need to verify the input capacitance and
the tuning frequency.
Then we will define the antenna definition.
So first of all we need to define the format.
If it's an ID one card, an ID two card, ID three, etc., etc. so ID one card means a class one card
for example.
Then we need also to define the technology.
And finally the targeted inductance, the inductance that we need that we would like to have.
Third step is the antenna simulations.
So for the antenna we need to simulate the dimension of the antenna.
So we need to add the number of turns, the length the width the pitch etc. etc..
And finally we need to validate this antenna.
So we need to perform an inductance measurement.
We need to check that everything is fine of what we have, choose as an antenna and etc. etc..
Then we need to calculate the tuning frequency.
After that we need to check the loading effect, which means that the card doesn't, uh, doesn't have
a very high load, which doesn't decrease the field of the reader.
Then we need to check the mean, which is, uh, the the value, the lowest value of the field from
which the card start answering.
Because, for example, for a different type of classes for each card, as you have seen earlier, there
are different means.
For example, for a class one card h mean is equal to 1.5A/m.
So we need to check that our card can answer at at this h mean value of the field.
And finally we need to calculate the resonance frequency.
So after that for the antenna design, as we have said, the the integrated circuit vendor should provide
four parameters, which are the input capacitance, the antenna design recommendation, the antenna
format, and and the recommended tuning frequency.
After checking all of that, we can do the antenna definition.
So to define the antenna parameters we need to define the antenna shape as we have seen earlier, like
ID one, ID two or half, half the size, etc., etc. then we need to define the technology, for example
copper wire printing, PCB, etc. and finally the antenna impedance.
So we have the resonant frequency.
And through the resonant frequency we can calculate the inductance.
So as you have seen earlier, our resonance frequency f zero is equal to one divided by two multiplied
by p multiplied by root square of l multiplied by c, which gives us that uh, which gives us this formula
to calculate the inductance.
So after the antenna definition we need to simulate our antenna.
So first of all we need to simulate the antenna design to reach the targets.
Then we need to find the antenna dimensions.
Third step we need to find the physical parameters.
And finally choose a simulator to validate.
For example we have a simulated simulator provided by a website from St STMicroelectronics which is
for example this one.
So as you can hear, as you can see here in this website, we have different parameters that we can
play with until we get our value of the inductance.
For example here we can choose a random number of turns.
Then we can choose the antenna length.
For example let's say.
Uh, 50.
Then we have the antenna width.
Let's say let's keep it 45, for example.
Then for the conductor, we can play with the parameter width, spacing, thickness, etc., etc. and
then a very important parameter which is the thickness of the substrate.
So all these parameters give us an alternate result.
And the inductance for this is 1.1 micro Henry for example.
So.
And finally, for the antenna validation, we need to measure the inductance of the antenna.
And then we need to measure the tuning frequency of the integrated circuit plus the antenna.
So the whole group.
So which means the antenna plus the chip of the contactless cards.
And of course we need to choose the antennas with the resonance frequency following the integrated circuit
recommendation.